acquitting to 1.6 billion tons of food that spoiled on the way to the market or expired in our refrigerators or were simply thrown out by supermarkets and restaurants at the end of the day. Every single year, up to 600 million people will get sick eating contaminated food, highlighting the challenge that we have of maintaining global food safety. And, maybe unsurprisingly, the agricultural industry is the single largest consumer of fresh water, accounting for 70 percent of global usage. Now, you'll be relieved to know that the agricultural industry and that the global movement by universities, companies and NGOs is putting together comprehensive research and developing novel technology to address all of these issues. And many have been doing it for decades. But one of the more recent innovations in food production being deployed in industrial parks in North America, in the urban city centers of Asia,
descargando 1.6 miles de millones de toneladas de alimentos que se estropean de camino al mercado o caducan en nuestras neveras o que son desechados por supermercados y restaurantes al final del día. Cada año, hasta 600 millones de personas enfermarán por comer alimentos contaminados, destacando nuestro reto de mantener la seguridad alimenticia mundial. Y, quizá como era de esperar, la industria agrícola es la mayor consumidora de agua dulce, representando el 70 % del uso mundial. Ahora, estarán aliviados al saber que la industria agrícola y los movimientos globales llevados a cabo por universidades, empresas y las ONG están haciendo una investigación a fondo y desarrollando tecnología novedosa para enfrentarse a estos problemas. Y muchos lo han hecho durante décadas. Pero una de las innovaciones más recientes en la producción de alimentos que se utiliza en polígonos industriales de EE. UU., en núcleos urbanos de Asia
and even in the arid deserts of the Middle East is controlled environment agriculture. Controlled environment agriculture is actually just a fancy way of saying weather- or climate-proof farming, and many of these farms grow food three-dimensionally in vertical racks, as opposed to the two dimensions of conventional farms. And so this type of food production is also referred to as indoor vertical farming. I've been involved in the indoor vertical farming space for the past five and a half years, developing technology to make this type of food production more efficient and affordable. This picture was taken outside of a decommissioned shipping container that we converted into an indoor farm and then launched into the heart and the heat of Dubai. Indoor vertical farming is a relatively recent phenomena, commercially speaking, and the reason for this is that consumers care more about food safety and where their food comes from, and also, the necessary technology to make this possible is more readily available and lower cost, and the overall cost of food production globally is actually increasing, making this type of food production more competitive. So if you want to build an indoor vertical farm, you will need to replace some of the conventional elements of farming with artificial substitutes, starting with sunlight. In indoor vertical farms, natural sunlight is replaced with artificial lighting like LEDs. While there are many different types of LEDs being used, the one that we decided to install here is called "full spectrum LEDs," which was optimized for the type of vegetables that we were growing. Also, in order to maximize production for a given space, indoor vertical farms also utilize and install racking systems to grow vegetables vertically, and some of the biggest facilities stack their production 14 to 16 floors high. Now most of these farms are hydroponic or aeroponic systems, which means that instead of using soil, they use a substitute material like polyurethane sponges, biodegradable peat moss and even use inorganic materials like perlite and clay pellets. Another unique aspects about these farms is that they use a precise nutrient formula that is circulated and recycled throughout the facility, and this is pumped directly to the vegetables' root zone to promote plant growth. And lastly, these farms use a sophisticated monitoring and automation system to significantly increase productivity, efficiency and consistency, and these tools also provide the added benefit of producing food that is more traceable and safe. Some of the obvious benefits of growing food in this way is that you have year-round vegetable production,
e incluso en desiertos áridos de Oriente Medio es la agricultura en ambiente controlado. Agricultura en ambiente controlado es una forma elegante de decir agricultura a prueba de clima o ambiente, y muchos de esos cultivos producen alimentos tridimensionalmente en estantes, al contrario de las dos dimensiones de los cultivos tradicionales. Este tipo de producción de alimentos también se conoce como cultivos verticales de interior. Estuve involucrado en el cultivo vertical interior durante los últimos 5 años y medio creando tecnología para que esta clase de producción sea más eficaz y sostenible. Esta fotografía se tomó desde el exterior de un contenedor abandonado que convertimos en un cultivo de interior y después lo llevamos al corazón y al calor de Dubái. El cultivo vertical de interior es un fenómeno relativamente nuevo, en términos comerciales, y la razón es que a la gente le importa la seguridad alimentaria y la procedencia de sus alimentos y que también la tecnología necesaria para que esto sea posible es accesible más fácilmente y tiene un coste menor, y el coste total de producción de alimentos está aumentando mundialmente, provocando que esta producción sea más competitiva. Así que si desean levantar un cultivo vertical de interior deberán sustituir algunos de los elementos tradicionales del cultivo con sustitutos artificiales, empezando con la luz solar. En cultivos verticales de interior la luz natural es sustituida por luz artificial como lámparas LED. Aunque se usan muchos tipos diferentes de lámparas LED, las que pusimos aquí se llaman "lámparas LED de amplio espectro", óptimas para el tipo de vegetales que cultivábamos. Además, para maximizar la producción en un espacio concreto, los cultivos verticales de interior incluyen estructuras de estanterías para cultivar vegetales verticalmente, y en algunas instalaciones grandes apilan su producción entre 14 y 16 pisos de altura. Ahora muchos de esos cultivos son hidropónicos o aeropónicos lo que significa que en vez de tierra utilizan un material sustituto como esponjas de poliuretano, sustrato biodegradable e incluso materiales inertes como perlita y bolitas de arcilla. Otra cualidad única de estos cultivos es el uso de una fórmula nutritiva concreta que circula y se recicla en toda la instalación, y esta se bombea directamente a la raíz de los vegetales para su crecimiento. Y, por último, estos cultivos utilizan un circuito sofisticado de monitoreo y automatización para aumentar de forma notable la productividad, eficacia y consistencia, y dichas herramientas otorgan el beneficio extra de que producir alimentos sea más trazable y seguro. Algunos de los beneficios evidentes de producir alimentos de este modo son que puedes tener producción vegetal todo el año,
you have consistent quality and you have predictable output. Some of the other major benefits include significant resource use efficiencies, particularly water. For every kilogram of vegetables grown in this way, hundreds of liters of water is conserved compared to conventional farming methods. And with the water savings come similar savings in the use of fertilizer. One of the highest-yielding farms grows over 350 times more food per square meter than a conventional farm. And weatherproofing means complete control of incoming contaminants and pests, completely eliminating the need for the use of chemical pesticides. And not to be mistaken, these farms can produce enormous amounts of food, with one of the biggest facilities producing 30,000 heads of vegetables a day.
calidad constante y previsible rendimiento del producto. Otro beneficio importante es el gran uso eficiente de los recursos, en especial el agua. Por cada kilo de vegetales cultivados así, se ahorran cientos de litros de agua en comparación con el cultivo tradicional. Y junto al ahorro de agua también se ahorra en el consumo de fertilizante. Un cultivo con mayor rendimiento produce 350 veces más alimentos por metro cuadrado que un cultivo normal. Y la impermeabilización supone un control total de nuevos contaminantes y plagas, eliminando por completo el uso de pesticidas químicos. Y para no equivocarnos, estos cultivos pueden producir enormes cantidades de alimentos, con una instalación grande que produce 30 000 piezas de vegetales al día.
However, as with any new technology or innovation, there are some drawbacks. As you would imagine, growing food in this way can be incredibly energy-intensive. Also, these farms can only produce a small variety of vegetables commercially and the overall cost of the production still is quite high. And in order to address these issues, some of the biggest and most sophisticated farms are making significant investments, starting with energy efficiency. In order to reduce the high energy usage, there are efforts to develop higher-efficiency LEDs, to develop lasers optimized for plant growth and using even fiber-optic cables like these to channel sunlight directly into an indoor vertical farm during the day to reduce the need for artificial lighting. Also, to reduce the labor costs associated with hiring a more sophisticated,
Sin embargo, como con cualquier nueva tecnología o innovación hay algunos inconvenientes. Como podrán imaginar, producir alimentos así puede ser muy intensivo en energía. Además, estos cultivos solo producen una pequeña variedad de vegetales comerciales y el coste total de la producción todavía es bastante alto. Y para tratar estos problemas, algunos de los cultivos más grandes y sofisticados están haciendo importantes inversiones, comenzando por la eficiencia energética. Para reducir el alto consumo de energía, se están desarrollando lámparas LED de mayor eficacia, para crear láseres optimizados para el crecimiento del vegetal e incluso se usan cables de fibra óptica como estos para encauzar la luz solar directa a un cultivo vertical de interior durante el día para reducir la falta de luz artificial. Además, para reducir los costos de contratar mano de obra más sofisticada,
more urban and also more high-skilled labor force, robotics in automation is used extensively in large-scale facilities. And you can never really be too resource-efficient. Building indoor vertical farms in and around urban city centers can help to shorten the agricultural supply chain and also help to maintain the nutritional content in vegetables. Also, there are food deserts in many countries that have little to no access to nutritious vegetables, and as this industry matures, it will become possible to provide more equitable access to high-quality, highly nutritious vegetables in even the most underprivileged of communities. And finally, and this is really exciting for me personally, indoor vertical farming can actually be integrated seamlessly into the cityscape to help repurpose idle, underutilized and unused urban infrastructure. In fact, this is already happening today. Ride-sharing services have taken hundreds of thousands of cars off the road and they have significantly reduced the need for parking. This is a farm that we installed in central Beijing in an underutilized underground parking structure to grow vegetables for the nearby hotels. Underutilized infrastructure is not simply limited to large-scale civil engineering projects, and they can also include smaller spaces like idle restaurant corners. This is an example of a farm that we installed directly into the partition of a hotel entrance in order to grow fresh herbs and microgreens on-site for the chefs. Honestly, if you look around, you will find underutilized space everywhere, under, around and inside of urban developments. This is a farm that we installed into an empty office corner to grow fresh vegetables for the employees in nearby cafes. I get to be a part of all these cool projects and working in the agricultural industry to improve access and affordability to fresh and nutritious produce, hopefully soon by anyone anywhere, has been the greatest joy and also the most humbling and intellectually challenging thing I've ever done. And now that I've convinced you that agriculture can be quite sexy, you'll be surprised and shocked to know that I still have trouble fully articulating how and why I decided to work, and continue to work, in the agricultural industry. But a couple of years ago, I found a rather unique answer hiding in plain sight. You see, I read an article about how your name, particularly your last name, can have a strong influence on everything from your personality to your professional career. This is my Japanese last name: Oda. And the characters translate literally into "small farm." (Laughter) Thank you. (Applause)
más urbana y más cualificada, se usa mucho robótica en automatización en instalaciones a gran escala. Y realmente nunca puedes ser demasiado eficiente en recursos. Levantar cultivos verticales de interior dentro y alrededor de núcleos urbanos puede ayudar a acortar la cadena de suministro agrícola y puede ayudar a mantener el contenido nutricional de los vegetales. También hay desiertos alimentarios en muchos países que tienen poco o ningún acceso a vegetales nutritivos, y mientras este negocio evoluciona, será posible proporcionar un acceso más equitativo a vegetales de gran calidad, altamente nutritivos incluso en las comunidades más desfavorecidas. Y, por último, y esto es muy emocionante para mí, los cultivos verticales de interior pueden ser perfectamente integrados en el paisaje urbano para reutilizar infraestructura urbana libre, infrautilizada o sin uso. De hecho, esto ya sucede hoy. Los servicios de viajes compartidos han eliminado miles de coches de la carretera y reducido de forma notable la necesidad de aparcamiento. Este es un cultivo que pusimos en el centro de Pekín en un recinto de un aparcamiento subterráneo infrautilizado para producir vegetales para los hoteles cercanos. La infraestructura sin uso no se limita solo a proyectos de ingeniería civil a gran escala, también comprende espacios más pequeños como rincones de restaurante vacíos. Este es un ejemplo de un cultivo que sembramos directamente en la pared divisoria de la entrada a un hotel para producir hierbas frescas y microplantas in situ para los cocineros. Francamente, si miran a su alrededor, encontrarán espacios sin utilizar por todas partes, debajo, alrededor y dentro de elementos urbanos. Este cultivo lo sembramos en un rincón de oficina vacío para producir vegetales frescos para la plantilla en cafeterías cercanas. Puedo ser parte de todos estos proyectos geniales y trabajar en la industria agrícola para mejorar el acceso y la asequibilidad a los productos frescos y nutritivos; con suerte pronto todos podrán estén donde estén, esto ha sido la mayor alegría y también el desafío más humilde e intelectual que hice nunca. Y ahora que les he convencí de que la agricultura puede ser muy atractiva, se sorprenderán y quedarán conmocionados al saber que aún tengo problemas expresando por completo cómo y por qué decidí trabajar, y seguir trabajando en la industria agrícola. Pero hace un par de años, hallé una respuesta muy singular oculta a simple vista. Verán, leí un artículo sobre cómo tu nombre, en especial tu apellido, puede influir notablemente en todo, desde tu personalidad hasta tu carrera profesional. Este es mi apellido japonés: Oda. Y los caracteres se traducen literalmente como "pequeño cultivo." (Risas) Gracias. (Aplausos)